lead411.com 2019-08-27

# Lead411 Privacy Policy - Lead411 Sales and Marketing Intelligence

We’ve recently updated our Privacy Policy to comply with the new requirements under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our policy has been updated in order to improve transparency and clarity of our data processes.

This policy applies where we are acting as a data processor with respect to your personal data.  This policy does not explain what other parties may do with any user information that may be provided to them.

We collect the following types of information about you:

Information you provide us directly:

We ask for certain information such as your username, real name, address, phone number and e-mail address when you register for a lead411 account, or if you correspond with us. We use this information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.

Information we may receive from third parties:

We may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you access our websites or Service through a third-party connection or log-in. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to the lead411 Service. You may also unlink your third-party account from the Service by adjusting your settings on the third-party service.

How do we collect our B2B data?

Lead411 provides business data that we get from a number of sources; a) Our research team that gets information from publicly available information, b) Users provide data about themselves or other companies & people, c) We license data from other data providers.

Opt-out:

You can opt out of our database at any time here – <https://www3.lead411.com/remove-a-page/>

Analytics information:

We continuously improve our websites and our products, and we may utilize different third-party web analytics tools to help us do so. We are interested in how visitors use our websites, our desktop tools, mobile applications, or our API, what they like and dislike, and where they have problems. Our products, desktop tools, mobile applications and API use analytical tools to understand feature usage patterns, to enhance and improve your product experience and offer you specific usage tips and guidance. In connection with normal business operations, as well as to increase functionality and enhance your user experience, this usage information may be linked to personal information that we have about individual users. We maintain ownership of this data and we do not share this type of data about individual users with third parties.  This information is used solely to assist us in maintaining a more effective and useful websites and products for our customers. This data will not be shared with third parties without your prior consent or unless required by law.

Cookies information:

Full details can be found on our Cookie Policy. When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets lead411 help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use the Service (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on the Service) and allow us or our business partners to track your usage of the Service over time. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. Full details can be found on our Cookie Policy.

Log file information:

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser or mobile device each time you access the Service. When you use our Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

Device identifiers:

When you access the Service by or through a mobile device (including but not limited to smart-phones or tablets), we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers,” such as a universally unique identifier (“UUID”). Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by lead411. A device identifier may convey information to us about how you browse and use the Service. A device identifier may remain persistently on your device, to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Service. Some features of the Service may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers is impaired or disabled.

Location data:

When you access the Service by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. Location data may convey to us information about how you browse and use the Service. Some features of the Service, particularly location-based services, may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

Commercial and marketing communications:

We use the information we collect or receive, such as your email address, to communicate directly with you. We may send you emails containing newsletters, promotions, and special offers. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you will be given the option to opt out or change your preferences. We also use your information to send you Service-related emails (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). You may not opt out of Service-related emails. You may also be able to be “found” on lead411 based on information that you provide (see “Find friends on lead411”) above.

Use of certain service type information we collect about you:

We use or may use cookies, log file, device identifiers, location data and clear gifs information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) to provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in; (g) to provide advertising to your browser or device, and (h) automatically update the lead411 application on your mobile devices.

What happens in the event of a change of control:

We may buy or sell/divest/transfer the company (including any shares in the company), or any combination of its products, services, assets and/or businesses. Your information such as customer names and email addresses, User Content and other user information related to the Service may be among the items sold or otherwise transferred in these types of transactions. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcies, dissolutions, reorganizations, liquidations, similar transactions or proceedings involving all or a portion of the company.

Instances where we are required to share your information:

Lead411 will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use or to protect the security, quality or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of lead411, our Users, or others.

How We Store and Protect Your Information

Storage and Processing:

Your information collected through the Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which lead411 or its subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities. lead411 may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which lead411 or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

Keeping your information safe:

In the event you are provided with an opportunity to establish and account or profile on our site, you may be able to access your Personally Identifiable Information with your password and username. This password is encrypted. We advise against sharing your password with anyone.  If you access your account via a third-party site or service, you may have additional or different sign-in protections via that third-party site or service. You need to prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-in mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer, browser, or mobile device by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. If we believe that the security of your information may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. 

We are committed to taking all reasonable precautions to safeguard the privacy of personal information which has been provided by its users. We use technical, contractual, administrative and physical security steps to protect your personal information. Security measures such as restricted access and the use of passwords and encryption have been adopted to protect your personal information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. Our employees have been trained to respect your privacy at all times and those employees with access to your personal information shall use your personal information strictly in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Please be aware that no data transmission over the Internet or via e-mail is completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee protection of all personal information in all cases. For example, we cannot guarantee protection against interception, misappropriation, misuse, or alteration, or that your information will not be disclosed or accessed by the unauthorized acts of others. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. 

Compromise of information:

In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, lead411 will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests. As noted above, you may not opt out of Service-related communications (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). If you have any questions about reviewing or modifying your account information, you can contact us directly at support@lead411.io.

Opting out of collection of your information for Tracking / Advertising:

Please refer to your mobile device or browser’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. Depending on your type of device, it may not be possible to delete or disable tracking mechanisms on your mobile device. Note that disabling cookies and/or other tracking tools prevents lead411 or its business partners from tracking your browser’s activities in relation to the Service, and for use in targeted advertising activities by third parties. However, doing so may disable many of the features available through the Service. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us directly at support@lead411.io.

How long we keep your private profile information:

Following termination of your User account, lead411 may retain your private profile information for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes. For the avoidance of doubt, any information that you choose to make public on the service may not be removable.

Information for Users in Europe and Elsewhere Outside the U.S.:

If you use our site or services outside of the United States, you agree that we may collect, process, and store your personal information in the United States and other countries. The laws in the U.S. regarding personal information may be different from the laws of your country. Any such transfers will comply with safeguards as required by relevant law.

Changes to this Policy:

Lead411 reserves the right to modify this privacy policy from time to time, so please review it regularly. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, and/or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the changes becoming effective.

**Additional terms that apply to some residents of the European Economic Area (EEA)  **

In this section we have set out:

  1.       the general categories of personal data that we may process;
  2.       the purposes for which we may process personal data; and 
  3.       the legal bases of the processing; and
  4. how we may share you information; and
  5. additional rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you.

What kind of Personally Identifiable Information do we collect and how we use it. 

  1.       we may use or share Personally Identifiable Information to provide products and/or service to you, to enable third-parties to provide products and/or services to you, to enhance the operation of the Service, improve our marketing and promotional efforts, analyze use of the Service, and tailor your experience with third parties as provided below in this Privacy Policy. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, resolve disputes, accomplish administrative tasks, contact you, enforce our agreements with you, including our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy, and to comply with applicable law and cooperate with law enforcement activities. 
  2.       we may process data about your use of our website and services (“usage data”). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your website and services usage. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website and Service. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and service. 
  3.       we may process your account data (“account data”).  The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our Service, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services. 
  4.       we may process your information included in your personal profile on our website (“profile data”).  The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, and company name.  The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services. 
  5.       we may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data”). The transaction data may include first and last names, an email address to be used as a login, billing contact information, credit card number and a password. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests.   
  6.       we may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data”). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication.  Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is your consent or our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services. 
  7.       we may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others. 
  8.         in addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 3, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. 
  9.         please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us unless we prompt you to do so and you have that person’s authorization to provide such, which we may verify via a method chosen in our sole discretion. 

Non-Personally Identifiable Information. 

Non-Personally Identifiable Information is information that does not identify a specific person. This type of information may include things like the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website you visited before coming to the Site or otherwise participating in the Service, the URL of the website you visit after leaving the Site, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, mobile carrier information, mobile device information, or general and/or aggregated location data that does constitute Personally Identifiable Information. We, and/or our authorized third parties may automatically collect this information when you visit or use the Service using electronic tools like Cookies and Web beacons or Pixel tags, as described below in this Privacy Policy.  We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, administer the Services, analyse trends, gather demographic information, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. We may also share this information with our authorized third parties to measure the overall effectiveness of our products and services.

Providing your personal data to others.

We may disclose your personal data to one or more of those selected third-party providers of products or services on or linked from our website, identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to provide you with products.  

In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this section, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

Release of Non-Personally Identifiable Information. 

We may disclose or share Non-Personally Identifiable Information with third party service providers and the public. For example, we may share aggregated demographic information (which does not include any Personally Identifiable Information) or use third party service providers to track and analyze Non-Personally Identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our users to administer our services. We may also publish this aggregated information for promotional purposes. Such data is collected on our behalf and is owned and used by us.

Choices on Collection/Use of Information. You can always choose not to provide certain information, although a certain level of information is required to engage and participate in the Service.

In addition to the rights already recorded above, if you are based in the EEA, you may have the following additional rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you:

Additional Rights. 

In this Section we have summarized the rights that you may have under data protection laws in the EEA. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under data protection laws in the EEA are:

  1.   the right to access;
  2.   the right to rectification;
  3.   the right to erasure;
  4.   the right to restrict processing;
  5.   the right to object to processing;
  6.   the right to data portability;
  7.   the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and 
  8.   the right to withdraw consent.

You have the right to confirmation as to whether we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, considering the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully process. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

          (a)    consent; or

          (b)    that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection.

You may access your personal information that we hold by contacting us using the contact details contained in Section 12 above.  We will provide you with a copy of the personal information we keep about you. However, we reserve the right to charge you a reasonable amount for providing copies of any personal information you request, to take into account the time, cost and effort involved.

You may request that the personal information we hold about you be corrected by contacting us.  If we do not agree to your request for a correction, you may then request that we take reasonable steps to attach to the information a statement of the correction sought but not made. 

Please be aware that some of these rights may be limited or unavailable where we have an overriding interest or legal obligation to continue to process the data, or where data may be exempt from disclosure.

**Notice of Privacy Rights to California Residents** **.  **

California law requires that we provide you with a summary of your privacy rights under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Civil Code 1798.83”), the California Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and beginning January 1, 2020, the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”). 

California Civil Code 1798.83 (the “Shine the Light” law).

Under Civil Code 1798.83 users who are California residents may request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year.  If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

California Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”)

In addition to the rights noted above, COPPA further requires us to allow you to control who you do not want us to share that information with. To obtain this information, please send a request by email to the address found below. When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what Personally Identifiable Information you do not want us to share with our marketing partners. Please allow 30 days for a response. Also, please note that there is no charge for controlling the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information or requesting this notice.

California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”)

The CCPA also provides the right to opt out from the sale of personally identifiable information to third parties.  In addition, the CCPA provides you the right to access and delete personal information for California residents. To either this opt-out and/or how to delete personal information please send a request by email to the address found below. When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what personally identifiable information you do not want us to share with our marketing partners and how you can access and delete personally identifiable information.

Email: [support@lead411.io](mailto:support@lead411.io)
